<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on jeslacourse</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on jeslacourse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2020/12/01/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/01/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>California Canvass Map</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/california-canvass-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/california-canvass-map/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll likely be revisiting this project in the future to see how my analysis has changed. With that said, I&amp;rsquo;m presenting this project as I did in 2016. So much has changed in the last four years. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to rework this project and pull in some fresh data. It should make for a very interesting before-and-after.
Final product, top left, with the three layers used for analysis and composition{% include gallery id=&amp;ldquo;gallery&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;Paper Map Examples at Regional, District and City Levels&amp;rdquo; %}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Choice in Classification of Kernels</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/feature-choice-in-classification-of-kernels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/feature-choice-in-classification-of-kernels/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
Frequently, k-nearest neighbors classification is applied with features chosen arbitrarily, while `k` is adjusted to improve the accuracy of the model. For this experiment, `k` is fixed. Using correlations with the strict acknowledgement that all features are continuous, a feature set with high correlation within itself is selection. Visual analysis using density and scatter plots show that these features also share distinct distributions and thusly make great candidates for k-nearest neighbors clustering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Commands</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/git-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/git-commands/</guid>
      <description>The original post is a response to a class forum. This post is just a handy way to determine how the site will handle markdown language while also providing some interesting content.
This was originally part of a response to #151, but it should be good information for anyone trying to troubleshoot git version control. I&amp;rsquo;ve pulled some of the specific troubleshooting out and added a bunch of detail on the common commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights and Facets for Visualizing Categorical Data</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/highlights-and-facets-for-visualizing-categorical-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/highlights-and-facets-for-visualizing-categorical-data/</guid>
      <description>Side-by-Side Comparison of (a) Generic Plot and (b) Faceted Plots with Highlight
Visualizing Categorical Data What&amp;rsquo;s the most effective way to visualize comparisons between variable factors? How do you share a lot of information without muddying up your visualizations? There definitely isn&amp;rsquo;t one answer, but here&amp;rsquo;s one solution: faceted plots with gghighlight.
For sample data, I’m setting up two normal curves with offset sample means x̄ = ± 2. While we&amp;rsquo;re using two factors for simplicity, this method actual becomes more effective when the number of factors increases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation and Organization</title>
      <link>/1/01/01/motivation-and-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/1/01/01/motivation-and-organization/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m excited. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long road trying to find the right platform to build on. Fortunately, hosting on GitHub Pages, along with the incredible development of the Jekyll-based Minimal Mistakes theme has made web-development a (relatively) seamless task for integrating my projects from GitHub. I&amp;rsquo;ll post source code and repositories as reasonable. Some of the projects are University-based and don&amp;rsquo;t change much year-to-year. In those cases, sorry kids. Check out the end result but we can&amp;rsquo;t make it that easy for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
