<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about on jeslacourse</title>
    <link>/tags/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in about on jeslacourse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/tags/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/experience/</guid>
      <description>Seeking work with a community-oriented and socially conscious organization to promote social awareness through meaningful data interpretation and visualization
Data Management and Statistical Highlights
Creation and implementation of voter outreach GIS database for California&amp;rsquo;s 20,000 precincts
Adopted in part by major 2016 Presidential candidate campaign Primary role in data management/conversion project of approximately 500,000 entries
Earned commendations and national recognition from top management within firm
Custom built an intuitive, dynamic Excel vehicle maintenance workbook for 12 vehicle fleet with accompanying Fleet Procedures Manual</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>B.S. Statistics - Data Science Track
Minor - Computer Science
Highlights Big Data &amp;amp; High Performance Statistical Computing High-performance computing in high-level data analysis languages; different computational approaches and paradigms for efficient analysis of big data; interfaces to compiled languages; high-level parallel computing; MapReduce; parallel algorithms and reasoning. Python. R. SQL.
Categorical Data Varieties of categorical data, cross-classifications, contingency tables, tests for independence. Multidimensional tables and log-linear models, maximum likelihood estimation; tests of goodness-of-fit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
